Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Information Center Printed Materials, 1971-2000 RL.00672
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Information Center printed materials
1971-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office
RL.00672
39 Linear Feet
Established in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The Chicago Office opened in 1891. The Information Center served as a corporate research library and reference center for the agency. Collection spans the years 1971-2000 and consists largely of trade publications produced by commercial publishers, academic institutions, professional associations and market research firms. Publications address a broad range of market sectors, product categories, demographics and consumer behaviors. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
28,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Information Center Printed Materials were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2002.
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1971-2000 and consists largely of trade publications produced by commercial publishers, academic institutions, professional associations and market research firms. Publications address a broad range of market sectors, product categories, demographics and consumer behaviors.
Collection Arrangement
Materials have not been ordered or described beyond their original condition.
Serials (Publications); Marketing research; Marketing research -- United States; Demographic surveys; Demographic surveys -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office
- Printed Materials, 1971-2000
  - About Women and Marketing, 1996-1997, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - All About Women Consumers, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Boomer Report, 1994-1997, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Credit Card News, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Entertainment Marketing Letter, 1997-2000, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Forecast, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Iconoculture, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - IEG Sponsorship Report, 1997 (Box 1)
  - IEG Sponsorship Report, 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Impact, 1990-1997, 8 folders (Box 2)
  - Impact, 1986-1989, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Interactive Consumers, 1994-1997, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Licensing Letter (TLL International), 1996-1999 (Box 3)
  - Lookout Foods, 1998 July-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Lookout Foods, 1996-1998, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Lookout Foods, 1994-1995, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Lookout Foods, 1992-1994, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Lookout Foods, 1990-1992, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Lookout Foods, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Lookout Non-Foods, 1997-1998, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Lookout Non-Foods, 1995-1996, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Lookout Non-Foods, 1993-1995, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Lookout Non-Foods, 1991-1993, 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Lookout Non-Foods, 1990-1991, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Roper Reports 96-8, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Roper Reports 96-6, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Roper Reports 96-6 through 96-2, 1996 (Box 13)
  - Roper Reports 96-1, 95-10, 95-9, 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Research Alert, 1994-1996, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Research Alert, 1992-1994, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Selling to Seniors, 1992-2000, 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Starch Tested Copy, 1989-1991 (Box 16)
  - Trend Letter, 1994-1997, 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Tufts University Health and Nutrition Letter, 1993-1997, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - University of California-Berkeley Wellness Letter, 1996-1997 (Box 16)
  - University of California-Berkeley Wellness Letter, 1993-1995 (Box 17)
  - Roper Reports 92-2, 92-1, 91-10, 91-9, 1991-1992 (Box 17)
  - Roper Reports 91-8 through 91-3, 1991 (Box 18)
  - Roper Reports 91-2, 91-1, 90-1, 90-2, 90-4, 1990-1991 (Box 19)
  - Roper Reports 90-3, 90-5 through 90-8, 1990 (Box 20)
  - Maturing Marketplace, 1996 (Box 21)
  - Mayo Clinic Health Letter, 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Media Industry Newsletter, 1997 (Box 21)
  - Minority Markets Alert, 1992-1993 (Box 21)
  - Nilson Report, 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - Research Alert, 1997-1998 (Box 21)
  - Maturing Marketplace, 1997 (Box 22)
  - Marketing to Women, 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Marketing to the Emerging Majorities, 1999 (Box 22)
  - Roper Reports 90-10, 90-9, Index, 1990-1991 (Box 22)
  - Minority Markets Alert, 1994-1999, 4 folders (Box 23)
  - Media Industry Newsletter, 1994-1996, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Roper Reports 80-1 through 80-6, Indices, 1980-1981 (Box 24)
  - Roper Reports 81-3 through 81-10, 1981 (Box 25)
  - Roper Reports 81-2 through 80-7, 83-10, Indices 1973-1980, 1980-1981 (Box 26)
  - Roper Reports 82-1 through 82-8, Index 1973-1983, 1982-1983 (Box 27)
  - Roper Reports 83-1 through 83-7, 1983 (Box 28)
  - Roper Reports 82-9, 82-10, 83-8, 83-9, 84-1, 84-2, Indices 1973-1984, 1982-1984 (Box 29)
  - Roper Reports 84-3 through 84-8, 1984 (Box 30)
  - Roper Reports 84-9 through 85-4, 1984-1985 (Box 31)
  - Roper Reports 85-5 through 85-8, Indices 1973-1986, 1985-1986 (Box 32)
  - Roper Reports 85-9 through 86-5, 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Roper Reports 86-6 through 87-2, 1986-1987 (Box 34)
  - Roper Reports 87-3 through 87-8, 1987 (Box 35)
  - Roper Reports 87-9 through 88-3, Indices 1973-1988, 1987-1988 (Box 36)
  - Roper Reports 88-4 through 88-10, Index 1973-1989, 1988-1990 (Box 37)
  - Roper Reports 89-2 through 89-6, 89-9, 1989 (Box 38)
  - Roper Reports 88-6, 89-7, 89-8, 89-10, 92-3, 1988-1992 (Box 39)
  - Roper Reports 92-4 through 92-8, 1992 (Box 40)
  - Roper Reports 92-9 through 93-3, 1992-1993 (Box 41)
  - Roper Reports 93-4 through 93-8, 1993 (Box 42)
  - Roper Reports 93-9 through 94-3, 1993-1994 (Box 43)
  - Roper Reports 94-4 through 94-8, 1994 (Box 44)
  - Roper Reports 94-9 through 95-3, presentation, 1994-1995 (Box 45)
  - Roper Reports 95-4 through 95-8, 1995 (Box 46)
  - Standard Directory of International Advertisers and Advertising Agencies, 1985-1986 (Box 47)
  - Standard Directory of Worldwide Marketing, 1987-1989 (Box 47)
  - Standard Directory of Worldwide Marketing, 1990 (Box 48)
  - MacMillan Directory of International Advertisers and Agencies, 1991 (Box 48)
  - Standard Directory of Advertising Agencies, 1989-1990 (Box 48)
  - Standard Directory of Advertising Agencies, 1981-1984 (Box 49)
  - Standard Directory of Advertising Agencies, 1985-1988 (Box 50)
  - Standard Directory of Advertising Agencies, 1988-1989 (Box 51)
  - Survey of Buying Power Data Service, 1989 (Box 51)
  - Yankelovich Monitor, 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Yankelovich Monitor, 1984-1986 (Box 52)
  - Yankelovich Monitor, 1986-1987 (Box 53)
  - Yankelovich Monitor, 1981-1983 (Box 54)
  - Method of Approximating the Current Monitor Social Values Segmentation (Yankelovich), 1982 (Box 54)
  - The Underground Economy: A Social Values Perspective (Yankelovich), 1983 (Box 54)
  - Yankelovich Monitor, 1978-1981 (Box 55)
  - Demographics of the American Population (Yankelovich), 1980 (Box 55)
  - Yankelovich Monitor, 1976-1979 (Box 56)
  - Attitudes toward Work (Yankelovich), 1977-1978 (Box 56)
  - Briefings for Management (Yankelovich), 1977 (Box 56)
  - Expanded View of Social Values Systems (Yankelovich), 1976 (Box 56)
  - How America Spends Its Leisure Time (Yankelovich), 1976 (Box 56)
  - The Family (Yankelovich), 1977 (Box 56)
  - Yankelovich Monitor, 1972-1976 (Box 57)
  - PIB/LNA Magazine Advertising Analysis Reports: (Box 58)
    - Apparel, 1982 (Box 58)
    - Business and Financial, 1982 (Box 58)
    - Drugs and Toiletries, 1981-1982 (Box 58)
    - Food and Beverage, 1982 (Box 58)
    - General and Retail, 1982 (Box 58)
    - Home-Building, 1982 (Box 58)
    - Magazine Totals, Class Totals, 1982 (Box 58)
    - Transportation, 1982 (Box 58)
    - Apparel, 1981 (Box 59)
    - Business and Financial, 1981 (Box 59)
    - Food and Beverage, 1981 (Box 59)
    - General and Retail, 1981 (Box 59)
    - Magazine Totals, Class Totals, 1981 (Box 59)
    - Parent Company Index, 1981-1982 (Box 59)
    - Home and Building, Household, 1981 (Box 59)
    - Transportation and Agriculture, 1981 (Box 59)
  - Business Marketing, 1990-1993 (Box 60)
  - JWT Chicago Yearbook, 1999 (Box 60)
  - MPA Magazine Handbook, 2000 (Box 60)
  - Memory in a Jingle: Music as a Mnemonic Device in Communicating Advertising Slogans (Richard Yalch), 1991 (Box 60)
  - Oscar Mayer Cold Cut Facts (Olympic sponsorship), 1991 (Box 60)
  - Tagline checks, 1998 (Box 60)
  - What's New in Advertising and Marketing, 1997 Winter (Box 60)
  - Media Choices: Connecting with Consumers, 2000 (Box 60)
  - PIB/LNA Magazine Advertising Analysis Reports: (Box 61)
    - Business and Financial, 1980 (Box 61)
    - Drugs and Toiletries, 1980 (Box 61)
    - Food and Beverage, 1980 (Box 61)
    - Magazine Totals, Class Totals, 1980 (Box 61)
    - Parent Company Index, 1980 (Box 61)
  - Business Marketing, 1994 (Box 62)
  - PIB/LNA Magazine Advertising Analysis Reports:
    - Food and Beverage, 1979 (Box 62)
    - General Brand Index, 1980 (Box 62)
    - Apparel, 1979-1980 (Box 63)
    - Food and Beverage, 1978 (Box 63)
    - Home-Building, 1980 (Box 63)
    - Parent Company Index, 1978 (Box 63)
    - Transportation and Agriculture, 1980 (Box 63)
    - Business and Financial, 1979 (Box 64)
    - Drugs and Toiletries, 1979 (Box 64)
    - General and Retail, 1979 (Box 64)
    - Transportation and Agriculture, 1979 (Box 64)
    - Business and Financial, 1978 (Box 65)
    - General and Retail, 1978 (Box 65)
    - General Brand Index, 1978 (Box 65)
    - Drugs and Toiletries, 1979 (Box 66)
    - Home-Building, 1978-1979 (Box 66)
    - Magazine Totals, Class Totals, 1978 (Box 66)
    - Transportation and Agriculture, 1978 (Box 66)
  - The New Let There Be Neon (Rudi Stern), 1995 (Box 66)